#### **Mansi Phute**

My research focuses on the **security** and **explainability** of language and vision foundation models. I work on developing explanations for machine learning models and analyzing them to identify vulnerabilities in existing ML systems, then find solutions to mitigate these issues. My work spans a wide range of application areas, including robust multi-object tracking in computer vision, developing defenses against attacks on large language models, and understanding large language models and the insights they can give us into human interactions. I have also worked with 3D simulation software like CARLA and Unreal Engine.

mansiphute@gatech.edu

mphute.github.io

CV PDF

@mansiphute @mphute Google Scholar

#### Education

Ph.D. in Computer Science Fall 2022 —

Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, GA

M.S. in Computer Science Fall 2022 — Spring 2024

Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, GA

**B.Tech.** in Electronics and Telecommunication Fall 2018 — Spring 2022

Specialization: Machine Learning

Vishwakarma institute of Technology, Honors: Artificial Intelligence and Data Analytics

### Research Experience

Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, GA Summer 2022 — Present

Graduate Research Assistant School of Computational Science and Engineering

Advisor: Duen Horng (Polo) Chau

Member of the Polo Club of Data Science where we bridge and innovate at the intersection of data mining and humancomputer interaction to synthesize scalable, interactive, and interpretable tools that amplify human's ability to understand and interact with big data. Developed defences against adversarial attacks in Language and Vision domain.

Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, GA Spring 2023

> Graduate Teaching Assistant School of Computational Science and Engineering Mentor: Duen Horng (Polo) Chau

Nanyang Technological University, Singapore

Fall 2021 — Spring 2022 Undergraduate Research Assistant Cyber Security Research Centre at NTU (CYSREN)

Mentor: Thambipillai Srikanthan

Increasing python application security by analyzing libraries used. Developed dynamic dependency graph to trace vulnerabilities.

Nanyang Technological University, Singapore

Fall 2021 — Spring 2022

Spring 2021

Fall 2020

Summer 2019

Mentor: Thambipillai Srikanthan

Vishwakarma Institute of Technology, India

Automated human resource planning and forecasting by combining business intelligence of NHS, UK with data analytics

Undergraduate Research Assistant Cyber Security Research Centre at NTU (CYSREN)

to properly shift the HR planning from manual to automated

Undergraduate Research Assistant Associated with Dassault Systems

Mentor: Jyoti Madake

Developed AI based solutions for agricultural problems faced in India by usimg hyperspectral imaging to predict soil

fertility in the land

Vishwakarma Institute of Technology, India Undergraduate Research Assistant School of Electronics and Telecommunication

Mentor: Abha Marathe

Tech Mahindra Ltd, Pune, India

Conducted a thorough literature survey on the use of AI in finance and the various ways it is used for risk management in

the stock market

Intern, Web Development

Mentor: Rahul Bedmutha Developed a portal for internal use, using HTML, CSS and Javascript.

#### **Honors and Awards**

Marshall D. Williamson Fellowship

Awarded to a well-rounded, second-year Master's student who best embodies values of academic excellence and

leadership

Best Poster at BMVC'23 2023 Robust Principles was awarded the Best Poster award at BMVC

Best Scholar in ECE 2022

Merit-based award for the ECE student with the highest undergraduate GPA in the entire department

Best Student in ECE

One of the 3 students chosen as the best student in ECE department based on overall performance throughout undergrad

Second place in IEEE "One Million Seconds" Hackathon

Designed an autonomous system to support healthcare workers for cleaning the isolation wards in COVID-19 hospitals in India. First Runner Up from a total of 1200 participants

### **Publications**

Semi Truths: A Large-Scale Dataset for Testing Robustness of Al-Generated Image Detectors Anisha Pal, Julia Kruk, Mansi Phute, Manognya Bhattaram, Diyi Yang, Duen Horng (Polo) Chau, Judy

Hoffman

NeurIPS. 2024. 

**LLM Attributor: Interactive Visual Attribution for LLM Generation** 

Seongmin Lee, Zijie J. Wang, Aishwarya Chakravarthy, Alec Helbling, ShengYun Peng, Mansi Phute, Duen Horng (Polo) Chau,, Minsuk Kahng

ACL demo. 2024. Ø Project 
B PDF 
BibTeX

**Robust Principles: Architectural Design Principles for Adversarially Robust CNNs** 

ShengYun Peng, Weilin Xu, Cory Cornelius, Matthew Hull, Kevin Li, Rahul Duggal, Mansi Phute, Duen Horng (Polo) Chau, Jason Martin

BMVC. 2023. Project PDF 🕩 Code 🖽 Video 🛂 Poster 🗏 BibTeX 🏆 Best Poster Award

LLM Self Defense: By Self Examination, LLMs Know They Are Being Tricked

Mansi Phute, Alec Helbling, Matthew Hull, ShengYun Peng, Sebastian Szyller, Cory Cornelius, Duen Horng (Polo) Chau

ICLR Tiny Paper. 2024. 

### **Talks and Presentations**

Large Language Models and How They Work June 2024

Georgia Institute of Technology, Course on Large Language Models **★** Invited

LLM Self Defense: By Self Examinations, LLMs Know They Are Being Tricked! IBM, San Jose CA

## Press

April 2024 "Student Excellence Honored at Annual Event," Georgia Tech "GRE Success Stories: How Test Takers Scored Above the 90th Percentile," Jamboree August 2023

"Team Eklavya- E&TC; students team Designs Autonomous sanitisation robot," Vishwakarma Institute of May 2020

Technology

# **Teaching**

**Graduate Teaching Assistant** Spring 2023

Fall 2019

Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, GA Data and Visual Analytics (CSE 6242 / CX 4242), Instructor: Duen Horng (Polo) Chau I was a Teaching Assistant (TA) at Georgia Tech for the class Data and Visual Analytics where I worked with a team of 30

TAs to enable learning in a class of more than 1200 students. I was a part of designing homework and mentoring students in their course work and project work.

**Teaching Volunteer** 

Vishwakarma Institute of Technology, Pune, India Aashadeep: Literacy Program for underpriviledged people, Instructor:

A semester long teaching program where I created learning opportunities for increasing literacy in society aimed towards

people outside the traditional schooling age. Thus proving that there is no binding of age to learn how to read or write. This program aimed at combating illiteracy in specific sections of society.

#### **Grants and Funding Guaranteeing AI Robustness against Deception**

2023 - 2024Funded by DARPA: Defense Advance Research Projects Agency Pls: Cory Conelius (Intel Labs), Duen Horng (Polo) Chau (Georgia Tech)

# Service

Reviewer

NeurlPS Workshop on Socially Responsible Language Modelling (NeurlPS SoLaR) 2023

### Mentoring

Sri Ranganathan Palaniappan B.S. in Computer Science, Georgia Institute of Technology

## References

Dr. Polo Chau, Associate Professor School of Computational Science and Engineering

cc.gatech.edu/~dchau/ **Dr. Thambipillai Srikanthan**, Professor

Georgia Institute of Technology

School of Computer Science and Engineering Nanyang Institute of Technology www.ntu.edu.sg/scse/about-us/past-chairs/prof-thambipillai-srikanthan